<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>My Diary &#8211; Italianpot.com | Authentic Italian Recipes</title>
	<atom:link href="https://domsites.github.io/italianpot/category/my-diary/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://domsites.github.io/italianpot</link>
	<description>Authentic Italian Recipes</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 04:23:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://domsites.github.io/italianpot/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/cropped-IPfavicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>My Diary &#8211; Italianpot.com | Authentic Italian Recipes</title>
	<link>https://domsites.github.io/italianpot</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to cook pasta</title>
		<link>https://domsites.github.io/italianpot/how-to-cook-pasta/</link>
					<comments>https://domsites.github.io/italianpot/how-to-cook-pasta/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[italianpot]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Diary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooking Pasta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pasta and noodles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://italianpot.com/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How to cook pasta How do you cook pasta perfectly and tell when drain? The first tip that I can give you is to taste your food, the instinct helps a lot. But I think to make good dishes must put love and passion and even taste, so [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>How to cook pasta</h2>
<p><strong>How do you cook pasta perfectly and tell when drain?</strong></p>
<p>The first tip that I can give you is to taste your food, the instinct helps a lot. But I think to make good dishes must put love and passion and even taste, so that you can add salt or pepper, fix a salty dish etc.<br />
Today we explain how to cook different types of pasta perfectly. Simple but important rules to enjoy a real Italian pasta cooked to perfection. Cook the pasta in plenty of water.<br />
First of all, it is important since the amount of water in which the pasta cook: the relationship between pasta and water must be of 1 to 10 (for example, for 500 g of pasta, 5 liters of water are needed. Pour the pasta in boiling water only. The water should be boiling from the early stages of cooking, so the pasta is placed in salt water only when it bubbles vigorously. Do not forget to stir the pasta. After 20-30 seconds maximum pasta should be stirred with a scoop. The operation must be repeated if it is smooth paste, while if it is egg pasta is fine stir only in the first stage of cooking, to avoid breaking it. The egg pasta, in fact, is more delicate than that of semolina.</p>
<p><strong>Important:</strong> today many prefer the pasta not fully cooked, for more substantial to chew. A pasta of excellent quality should be cooked so that when tasting proves fully cooked, so you can best appreciate the taste and texture. Remember that less you cook the pasta, and the lower will be the : 100 g of uncooked pasta to 60-70% of the real time become ca. 220 g of cooked pasta, and if cooked at the correct time the weight increases by a further 10-15%.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://domsites.github.io/italianpot/how-to-cook-pasta/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The real Pizza alla Marinara</title>
		<link>https://domsites.github.io/italianpot/the-real-pizza-alla-marinara/</link>
					<comments>https://domsites.github.io/italianpot/the-real-pizza-alla-marinara/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[italianpot]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 02:33:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Diary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pizza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dough]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san marzano tomato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tomato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tomato Sauce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://demo.lyrathemes.com/kale-pro/?p=44</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The first was named “Mastunicola” (Master Nicola), a name that is not appropriate today, as well as being too ‘energetic’, composed of a stuffing of cheese and lard around the 600s, and later with the addition of pork cracklings! So around the 700s the Pizza [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The first was named “Mastunicola” (Master Nicola), a name that is not appropriate today, as well as being too ‘energetic’, composed of a stuffing of cheese and lard around the 600s, and later with the addition of pork cracklings!</p>
<p>So around the 700s the <a href="https://domsites.github.io/italianpot/pizza-dough/">Pizza</a> Marinara was born, an even more inappropriate name because it has nothing to do with the ocean (Marinara derives from “mare” meaning sea, and implies belonging or relative to the sea), being that its condiments are simply tomato, garlic, oregano, and extra virgin olive oil. Initially, this pizza’s toppings were only tomatoes and garlic, because these are plentiful, sometimes with the addition of anchovies or whitebait (very small fish), but only if the catch of the day was abundant and therefore less costly. All the other penniless had to settle nevertheless on simply tomato or at most with the addition of oil and oregano.</p>
<p>So it occurred that a pizza maker in the <a class="underline" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Port_of_Naples">port of Naples</a>, tired of the constant complaints of sailors who told him to “N’sapuriscila nu pocu,” to “give it some taste”, especially when the day’s catch had gone poorly, added an extra ingredient to the toppings that would not have an impact on the price.</p>
<p>And so he added garlic, and the pizza “Alla Marinara” was born that was not topped with seafood, but which represented the sailor’s lunch!</p>
<h3>Enjoy the Real Pizza Alla Marinara!</h3>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://domsites.github.io/italianpot/the-real-pizza-alla-marinara/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
